Hello and welcome.  I heartily welcome you all
to Smart Investing YouTube channel where you will get daily stock
market updates.  So as you know, right now
we are doing
a series of quarterly Q1 results.
So under the same, today we are going to
talk about the
Q1 results that the company
presented on 15th July.  So in that
we will discuss about ICICI which is a general
insurance company.  So
before we see all that, I have a
small request for you that if you
are new to this channel then please subscribe and
also click on the bell icon so that you never
miss any important update.
So let's start the video.
So first of all let us see the Q1
results of ICICI Bank, let us
see a little about its
net income, see what I am doing,
you can also see the previous video in that and
in this also I am trying to
give you people the knowledge in detail.
So I'm not looking to
see that in a lot of short videos.  What is there in it is
that there is a certain format.  That's the way
he provides it.  But does it help you people
in taking any decision on that basis
or not?  This is very important for me to know.
And you also tell me that
whatever videos I am making right now and you are
watching them, then for how long are you watching them
and also tell me whether
you are able to
understand what I am saying?  If it is not coming then please
tell me that also so that I can
improve myself further.  Because the thing is that it takes
me some time to make all these videos
and I try my best to
tell you all the things
but it is possible that I may miss something.
So if you don't tell me then
I will not understand and I will continue like what
I am telling you now.
See, what I used to do previously was
that
I used to take data from some websites i.e. some websites of screeners
and now what I have done is that on the
basis of whatever results have come,
I have created a sheet and on the basis of that
I am extracting all the things and what I am doing is that I am
also taking some help of AI due to which it is becoming easy for
me to explain
and
I am able to tell you all the things which you actually
need.  Well, I have gained
a lot of knowledge.  Now let us
talk about this company.  So
what are we up to in this company right now?
We are going to talk about ICICI which is a general insurance.
So let's talk about net income.
When did this come?  It came on July 15th.  So right now
we are discussing it.  So
what happened in Q126 i.e. the first quarter is that your
net income has increased.  How many?  If
seen on a quarter on quarter basis, it is
almost 46.6%
which is a very good thing.  Due to which
many people got
attracted to it.  If
you look at the amount, it is showing profitability of almost around Rs 750 crore
because that is
net income.  Now why does net income increase?
Because it has very high net sales.
So, if you look at the net sales, quarter
on quarter, there has been an upside movement of almost 5%.  The
total of which is
around Rs 64000 crore.  Ok?  So what is this thing
doing?  It has a very high impact.
Due to which the net income has
increased so much.
What are the profit margins now?  Look, this is an insurance
company.  What kind of insurance?  General
Insurance.  See, life
insurance is a different segment.
What is there in it that it
depends on the person.  So what happens is that there are very
rare chances that some of the cards
expire and only then do we have to
give it to those companies.  Whatever sum is
insured has to be paid.  But what
happens in this general insurance category is that there is insurance for some non-living
elements, non-living
products like a house, a
motor car or any such thing
like if there is a cyber crime, there
is insurance for that too.  Many people
also take insurance on the crops they grow.
This company, which is actually a subsidiary of ICICI,
works on many such non-living elements like crop insurance.  So in this it becomes
very important for us to see many things.
Look, no
one would have told all this in such depth.  I am
trying to tell you everything.  So
you take out some time.  If you
spare a second and comment,
I will understand whether you
people like it or not.  Well,
now let us look at the profit margins,
which as I told you have some
impact, but still they have
maintained it quite well at
11.66%
and if seen from the last quarter, it is
almost 40%, which is very
good.  So we have come to know the highlights of so many things.
So what's in it?
So what is the actual reason for this growth,
as I told you, the profit which is
operational profit efficiency has
increased and the revenue growth which is our
sales has also increased.  What is the reason for this that there is a lot of
positive momentum in this stock and at the same time, the
most important thing is that
recently a partnership has been done with
Mahindra Finance, so
what will happen in that is that this
company will increase its sales in the rural areas.
What is there in this, Mahindra
Finance will also get positivity i.e. benefit
and ICICI General Insurance will also
benefit.  So what is it like in this way it is
a win-win situation for both the companies.
So, the data of this consumer of this company will go
to ICICI and the data of ICICI will go
to this company.  So in this
way both the companies are going to get
positive momentum or you can say
benefit.  So we have seen all these things
and at the same time,
another important thing is whether we should only
look at profitability or there are
other things in it which have just been dealt
with Mahindra Finance, whether it is positive
or not, it is also very important for us to see that.
So first of all we see
whether the profitability of the company is happening on the basis of the operational improvement of the company
or is it something else, then
we are coming to know that as we have
talked about earlier, this quarter's growth of 46.6% has happened
because its operations, that is, the
basic things of this company have increased and
due to this the profitability of this company has increased.
And if we look at the second point, what is this
deal with Mahindra Finance doing
?  There is a whole talk about showing sustainable growth
being in the future.
And if we look at the momentum,
that positive of the quarter is
going into the treasury only.  This means that the share price is
in upward momentum, which is
our first point.  That too
seems to be becoming possible here.  Now let's talk
about this partnership.  So as I told you, this is
in a rural area.  So what about this
that you people want to know what happens
in rural areas?  The maximum
thing that will be used is tractor,
what is the maximum use of tractor in rural areas.  It will be there in the
things of the crop.
Now, gradually,
many people in rural areas have also started buying cars or many other
things.
Rural areas are also developing slowly.
So when development is taking place, if we
go to rural areas then obviously we will
get a lot of positivity.  You will
get good gains.  So this means that at the right time, it is
said that the hammer should be struck only when the iron is hot.
So, if we look at it in that way,
now the rural areas have
moved on the path of development and the rural
areas are gradually developing.
So at this time, if we see that
this collaboration with Mahindra Finance can
give a lot of benefits
to ICICI General Insurance, then this is a
positive point.  But at the same time there are some
challenges also because
in this insurance sector we face a
lot of competition.
Ok?  If he wants, he can do the same thing that he has done
with Mahindra Finance.  It is possible that
some other company may partner with someone else
and the same thing is that
they provide the same type of product, the same thing
with some more benefits, so the problem in this is that there is a lot of
competition.  There
is also a lot of HDFC insurance.  ICICI also has it.
Many different regional ones are also
providing a good amount.  The government
also has it.  So what happens is that there are a lot of
challenges here.  So
if we ignore all these things, then if we
look at it overall, we have a lot of customers
in India because a lot of
people come from outside as well because we have a
huge customer base, so if we look at the customers,
we have a lot in India, so the company is
not going to have any problem, but
if its competitors
make the same product, then it will affect the
growth of this company, okay, so
what we have come to know from all these things is that
it is very important to diversify the revenue, it is
very important for us to see whether it is working for the long term or not, and at the same time, if we look at it, the
PE of the industry in which it works is 20.12, which is quite
good, but because no
such
PE ratio of ICICI LBAD is known yet because
some checking is being done on its valuation.
Meaning it is under scrutiny.  Ok?  So
we have to pay some attention to all these things
and we have already discussed all these things
that if you see in 5 years, then the
CAGR is almost around 15.78
and 50 and if you see in the financial year,
in the financial year 25,
its revenue growth has been so many crores.
And if you look at CHER, it is 16.01 and what is
notable is that there has been a growth of 30.74%.  If
you look at the return on equity, it is quite good, which we
can see as a positive point and it is
also showing improvement of almost 17.17% from last year.
If you look at all the other things, like the
strategic partnership it is doing, through this the
company has told us everything about
what are the challenges and what are not. Moreover, if
you look at the performance of this quarter, it has
increased significantly and the
analysts, who are big
institutional analysts, are also
giving a buy recommendation to the rating of this company,
but whether to invest or not
depends on you.  Now
if we look at the chart pattern of this company, then
since its inception it has been
going in positive direction.  How did this situation
come about which has come in every company due to Covid,
what is it like in every company that
losses were being incurred, so insurance companies have been
affected the most because they have to
repay, so at this time there
is a lot of negativity and after that the upward
momentum that has gone is positive and right now the
market sentiment is that businesses are closing
and many people are incurring losses, so
due to that this loss has been
tipped here and now it is giving positive momentum, so if
seen overall, what is its momentum, it is
upward, so it is important for us to pay attention to this company.
So now many
people might be asking
where can I get this sheet?  So as I
told you, if you go to the Screener website, then
go to the bottom of the quarterly result page and
you will get the PDF.  As soon as you
click there, you will get this PDF.
So it is important for many people to see this also.
So I do this too.  Total
Income Now look, this is not such a different thing.
Some of the things that I have mentioned earlier are provided by the company.
But it is important for you to know,
so I am showing it to you.  The first thing is
that whatever amounts there are, they are
in these lax.  So what we have to do is cut two first.
So look at this almost six
here, I will round the figure here.
608 has just come
in this quarter of June 30 and if we
look at the previous quarter, then in the March quarter
it was 585 so if you see it quarter on quarter,
as I told earlier,
it has increased a lot and if
you look at the previous year on year, it is 535, so in that too it has
increased a lot so
we have discussed the total income and
after that if you see the expenses, if you
see the expenses also, the total
expenses have also almost
crossed 542 and if you see here, if you see 543, then the
expenses are also sluggish stagnant so the
reason for this is that the overall
performance of the company has given a very good benefit
so if you see the profit after tax
here, then 74 747 which has come now
and the previous quarter was 509,
I can round it to 510 also and if you
look at it in the previous year, it
came around 580 so last  If you look at it from the quarter,
you will see that it is quite positive.  If you
look at last year, it is very positive.
Where will all these things affect you?  He
shares his earnings.  So
if you look at the earnings per share earlier, it
was around ₹11 which has now increased to
around ₹15.6.  So what we are getting to know from this is
that the performance of the company is
going in a positive trend and at the same time, the
tie up that the company has done with its other companies i.e. Mahindra Finance is
also going in a positive trend.
But one challenge is that as I
already told in the video, other companies may also
implement the same thing and
see their benefit.  So there are
advantages and
disadvantages of being the first mover.  Because
in First Advantage, do you take risk
and what are the other companies?  You are
taking a risk.  So what is the matter in this that they
leave it to you.  Just like they are successful,
what is the point of giving you the same benefits and giving you the same benefits at a lower price
?  Other companies come and capture the market.  The
same thing can happen here as Jio did in the telecom industry.
See, there is competition in every company
but we have to look at it from the business perspective
and if there is positive momentum in this business then
we have to invest.
Whatever future prospects the
analysts are saying, you should watch all these things on news channels,
whatever you get and whatever your
financial advisor says, you
can do accordingly.  Ok?  Ok?  So that's all
we keep in this video.  But more important than that is the
most
important point here, please see that.
Shareholding pattern.  If you look at the share holding pattern, the
promoters are
gradually reducing their shares.  Ok?  What
you see here is a gradual decline over the last three quarters.  Are you
buying FI?  If we
look at FIS, it is also decreasing.
But it has increased slightly in the last quarter.  If we
look at DIS, DIS
was increased in the last quarter, but what is it now?  Are decreasing.
So, where is this going?  In the hands of the public.
So, what is a public?  It is slowly
increasing now.  What does it mean?  That we do
n't have to buy this company?
Don't we have to buy this?  So, now you have to
see that the big hands have
almost 93% of the chances.
And how much does retail have?  Almost around 7%.
So the larger ends have more
quantity.  This means the company is safe.
Anyway, if it is associated with ICICI then it
means it is a subsidiary.  So big companies never commit that much
fraud.  But allegations have been raised against ICICI
also once.  So no
company is good unless it
gives us good benefits.  So
from that perspective, the company is fine.  Now
you have to decide whether to invest or not.
You can invest after consulting your advisor.
So if you are watching till here in the video then first of all
thank you.  If you are
new to the channel then please subscribe.  The
second channel is Rupi Investing,
you can also subscribe to that channel
so that I can provide videos to you people continuously.
See you in the next video, till then
Jai Hind.